MARIA MANUEL

mariamanuel.info@gmail.com

(415) 916-9449

Sacramento & San Francisco, CA 95691

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Driven lifelong learner seeking an opportunity to share knowledge, constantly learn and be challenged. Willingness to lend more than 15 years of expertise in managing multiple priorities. Eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent organizational skills.

SKILLS

OS: Windows, macOSDatabase: NoSQL, Access

· Software: MS Office, G Suite

CMS: WordPress

• Coding: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

• Coding: Python, Jinja, Linux

CERTIFICATIONS

M.E.D.A

 Front-end web development -November 2023

Kickstart Coding

 Back-end web development expected October 2024

CompTia

 A+ certification - expected June 2024

EDUCATION

City College of San Francisco Expected in 12/2024

Associate of Science: Information Technology

City College of San Francisco 06/2020

Associate of Science: Health Education

LINKS

- https://maria-manuel.com
- https://github.com/maria-manuel
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/maria-m-443143255/

WORK HISTORY

San Francisco Living Wage Coalition - Intern - Web Developer San Francisco, CA • 10/2022 - Current

- Collaborate effectively and communicate professionally with members of the development team.
- Shadow senior team members to learn new tasks.
- Problem-solve to determine appropriate debug/testing processes.
- Improve website functionality by updating plugins and extensions.
- · Troubleshoot and conduct standup of resolved technicalities.
- Craft strategy and intuitive interface to achieve prominent organizational purpose for internal and external clients.
- Coordinate with manager to obtain content for updates/expansions.
- Make recommendations for new features based on suitability and alignment with business goals.
- Maintained websites of 3 campaigns using best practices to serve diverse groups according to client's needs.
- Perform duties using attention to detail in design and web content using HTML and CMS.
- Manage 3 sites via WordPress content management system.

Volunteer Service - Caregiver

San Francisco, CA • 02/2015 - 07/2022

- Supervised and built strong relationship with seriously ill patient.
- Organized and supported activities of daily living.
- Documented sleep and eating patterns in medical record books.

McClellan & Corren - Legal Assistant

South San Francisco, CA • 10/2013 - 01/2015

 Act independently while supporting and monitoring database by proactively administering case development.

- Administered data by effectively utilizing best practices.
- Provided end-user support addressing desktop application issues.
- Assisted in management of projected workflow for rotating assistants.
- Surpassed firm objectives by cooperating with staff to implement project management initiatives and met projected deadlines by at least 1 day, ahead of schedule.
- Performed research and conferred with parties of all levels to gather, document and review information.
- Communicated effectively verbally and in writing as appropriate under the direction of attorneys.

Lewis, Brisbois, Bisgaard & Smith - Legal Assistant San Francisco, CA • 11/2011 - 06/2013

- Assist non-technical staff and attorneys with support addressing desktop application issues. Served as technical liaison.
- Modified database to accurately reflect case status documentation.
- Assisted department in added responsibilities to meet team goals with a positive attitude.
- Handled multiple projects simultaneously for 3 attorneys.
- · Responded to all clients professionally and courteously manner.
- · Proofread/edited a high volume of medical-legal records.

Law Offices Of Mullen & Filippi - Legal Secretary San Francisco, CA • 10/2006 - 10/2011

- Use initiative as the resident expert of desktop applications by utilizing all available resources.
- · Manage and maintain pertinent legal information in the database.
- Monitored cases while observing confidentiality with extreme discretion and delegated tasks.
- Proofread/edited court correspondence and medical summaries.
- Conferred with medical professionals of all levels including courthouses for research and gathered information.